<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>RTFM DevOps</title>
    <link>https://rtfmdev.github.io/docs/kubernetes/</link>
    <description>Recent content on RTFM DevOps</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rtfmdev.github.io/docs/kubernetes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://rtfmdev.github.io/docs/kubernetes/kubectl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rtfmdev.github.io/docs/kubernetes/kubectl/</guid>
      <description>kubectl cheatsheet Connection details To look at the connection details, we can either see the content of the ~/.kube/config file (on Linux) or run the following command:
$ kubectl config view Cluster info kubectl cluster-info When not using the kubectl proxy, we need to authenticate to the API server when sending API requests. We can authenticate by providing a Bearer Token when issuing a curl, or by providing a set of keys and certificates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://rtfmdev.github.io/docs/kubernetes/ingress/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rtfmdev.github.io/docs/kubernetes/ingress/</guid>
      <description>Ingress &amp;quot;An Ingress is a collection of rules that allow inbound connections to reach the cluster Services.&amp;quot;  To allow the inbound connection to reach the cluster Services, Ingress configures a Layer 7 HTTP/HTTPS load balancer for Services and provides the following:
TLS (Transport Layer Security) Name-based virtual hosting Fanout routing Loadbalancing Custom rules.  With Ingress, users do not connect directly to a Service. Users reach the Ingress endpoint, and, from there, the request is forwarded to the desired Service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://rtfmdev.github.io/docs/kubernetes/helm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rtfmdev.github.io/docs/kubernetes/helm/</guid>
      <description>Helm Helm package manager</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://rtfmdev.github.io/docs/kubernetes/advanced_tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rtfmdev.github.io/docs/kubernetes/advanced_tools/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://rtfmdev.github.io/docs/kubernetes/configMaps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rtfmdev.github.io/docs/kubernetes/configMaps/</guid>
      <description> ConfigMaps and Secrets </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://rtfmdev.github.io/docs/kubernetes/monitoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rtfmdev.github.io/docs/kubernetes/monitoring/</guid>
      <description>Services Monitoring Workflow Services Monitoring Workflow consists of three main components:
Collection agent, Metrics Server, and Dashboards.  Typical workflow, including most common components:
 Monitoring agent collects node metrics. cAdvisor collects containers and pods metrics. Monitoring Aggregation service collects data from its own agent and cAdvisor. Data is stored in the monitoring system’s storage. Monitoring aggregation service exposes metrics through APIs and dashboards.  A Few Notes:
 Prometheus is the official monitoring server sponsored and incubated by CNCF.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://rtfmdev.github.io/docs/kubernetes/networking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rtfmdev.github.io/docs/kubernetes/networking/</guid>
      <description>About Flanel: https://blog.laputa.io/kubernetes-flannel-networking-6a1cb1f8ec7c
A ServiceAccount is required to login. A ClusterRoleBinding is used to assign the new ServiceAccount (admin-user) the role of cluster-admin on the cluster.
cat &amp;lt;&amp;lt;EOF | kubectl create -f - apiVersion: v1 kind: ServiceAccount metadata: name: admin-user namespace: kube-system --- apiVersion: rbac.authorization.k8s.io/v1beta1 kind: ClusterRoleBinding metadata: name: admin-user roleRef: apiGroup: rbac.authorization.k8s.io kind: ClusterRole name: cluster-admin subjects: - kind: ServiceAccount name: admin-user namespace: kube-system EOF This means they can control all aspects of Kubernetes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://rtfmdev.github.io/docs/kubernetes/volume_types/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rtfmdev.github.io/docs/kubernetes/volume_types/</guid>
      <description>Volume Types A directory which is mounted inside a Pod is backed by the underlying Volume Type. A Volume Type decides the properties of the directory, like size, content, default access modes, etc. Some examples of Volume Types are:
emptyDir An empty Volume is created for the Pod as soon as it is scheduled on the worker node. The Volume&amp;rsquo;s life is tightly coupled with the Pod. If the Pod is terminated, the content of emptyDir is deleted forever.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>